# **Elizabeth Glenn Guy, PhD**

Email: elizabeth.guy86@gmail.com Phone: 425-829-5627

Github: https://github.com/elizabethguy86

Published Data Scientist with a unique blend of over six years of analytical and 3 years of technical sales, marketing, and project management experience. I bring enthusiasm, dedication, a collaborative attitude, and a critical questioning mindset to my work.

#### **Skills:**

Statistics: Expert in data collection, study design, and inferential statistics. Machine Learning and other Techniques: Linear and Logistic Regression, ANOVA, K Nearest Neighbors, PCA, Decision Trees, Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, Bayesian A/B Testing Statistical Software and Programming: Python, Pandas, Spark, SQL, SPSS, Excel Visualization: Matplotlib, Plot.ly, Tableau

# **Experience:**

### Data Science Fellow - Galvanize (Sept 2018 - Dec 2018):

- Conducted machine learning models to project sales, customer churn, detect fraud, and recommend new media for consumption. Utilized Regression, Gradient Boosting, Alternating Least Squares on AWS, and Random Forests.
- Created Run Recommender a running route suggestor utilizing the Strava API (pnwrun.org). Analyzed GPS coordinate data to suggest unique running routes matching user input metrics and plotted visible maps on working website.

## Technical Sales Engineer: Behavioral Neuroscience - Plexon, Inc (Oct 2015 – Sept 2018):

- Global customer sales- increased sales conversions of product lines by 20% and boosted sales of products by \$300,000
- Product management Prioritized feature development, troubleshoot, and test video tracking software. Spearheaded development of new technology Multi-Fiber Photometry System
- Provided technical customer support for video tracking, optogenetics, and high-throughput neurophysiology software

# Post-Doctoral Fellowship and Graduate Work in Behavioral Neuroscience - Wake Forest University, University of Toronto, Seattle Children's Research Institute (2008-2015):

- Independently conducted over 25 behavioral research studies presented findings at over 12 international academic conferences and author of 8 peer-reviewed original research papers
- Developed novel paradigm for pre-clinical trials testing smoking cessation pharmaceuticals (e.g., varenicline)
- Expert in complex mixed-model regression and ANOVA for significance testing of multiple variables on behavior indicating addiction-like properties. Also graduate training in psychometrics for survey design.

#### Course Instructor - University of Toronto, Antioch University in Seattle (2013 – 2015):

- Managed classes of up to 200 students and 2 teaching assistants independently prepared curriculum
- Expert in communicating complex technical information to technical and lay audiences

#### **Education**

**PhD Psychology**: Brain and Behaviour Concentration: University of Toronto

M.A. Experimental Psychology: Wake Forest University

**B.S. Psychology**: Appalachian State University, *Minor: Mathematics*